

Mieko Hirayama

Finance x UX Designer



miekohirayama76 @gmail.com







PROFILE

I am a passionate UX designer with experience in the front office of MUFG Bank's Asian corporate banking division. After five years in banking, I decided to change my career to UX designer to return to my creative roots. I am an enthusiastic, forward thinking and friendly individual with a proven ability to meet agreed deadlines and co-ordinate work with high accuracy in a fast moving environment. I may not have the most extensive design experience yet, but with my very strong soft skills combined with my solid understanding of user centred design principles and knowledge of the banking industry, I am sure I will add value to the team.

EDUCATION

CAREERFOUNDRY

Certified UX Designer, CAREERFOUNDRY, UK 2019

- 10 months intensive online course with 600h studying time
- Took specialisation in Frontend Development



MA Urban and Regional Planning, University of Liverpool, UK 2008



BA Architecture and Environment Systems,

Shibaura Institute of Technology, Tokyo Japan 2007

PROJECTS 2019

Recommended People - Communication app for homeowners and builders **±N Design** - Website for a florist start-up brand

TOOLS

Illustrator, Photoshop, Sketch, InVision, Balsamiq, Prott

SKILLS

Competitive analysis, User stories, User personas, User research, User flows, User journeys, Site mapping, Mobile-first design, Prototyping, Wireframing, Usability testing, HTML, CSS

PORTFOLIO - click here

EXPERIENCE

Customer Relations Team, Asian Corporate Banking Division

MUFG Bank, Ltd / Bank

London, U.K.

APRIL 2016 - PRESENT (3 years 1 month)

- Primary contact with over 40 corporate clients for fixing FX, deposit and loan rates
- Promoted MUFG online banking, FX trading and deposit confirmation platforms to clients
- Built relationships with customers and followed up with their business needs
- Analysed customer FX trades
- Worked closely with back office and branches across the world to follow up clients' payments and issues
- Created transaction tickets after every deal

Relations Manager Associate, Asian Corporate Banking Division

APRIL 2014 - APRIL 2016 (2 years 1 month)

- As relationship managers assistant, I handled daily queries from customers as well as preparing presentation documents for relationship managers
- Assisted clients' demands including account opening, management and payment issues
- Document administration (including KYC) focusing on details and productivity
- Liaise closely with relevant divisions within the bank and with the Head Office in Japan

KYC Administrator, Asian Corporate Banking Division

OCTOBER 2013 - APRIL 2014 (6 months)

- Completed over 80 cases of administration of KYC review per month
- Contacted customers via phone/e-mail and acquired the necessary documents

Buyer / Product Manager

MC Living Co., Ltd / Interiors Importer

Tokyo, Japan

APRIL 2011 - SEPTEMBER 2013 (2 years 5 months)

- Placed purchase orders to overseas vendors (main countries: China, India, Thailand and the Philippines - total orders of £1.5 million/year)
- Quality control of over 50 suppliers and 70 items at any one time

Sales / Product Designer

F.D.O. Co., Ltd / Jewellery Brand and Manufacturer Tokyo, Japan FEBRUARY 2010 - APRIL 2011 (1 year 2 months)

- Designed and prepared jewellery collection for client presentation
- Analysed customer demand, reflecting on product design and sales strategies